# Lee Alan Burton

## **Personal Details**

Nationality: British Place of Birth: U.K.

Email Address: leeburton@shu.edu.cn Twitter Handle: @leeaburton

Office Telephone: +86 021 6613 6129 Website: www.bmd-lab.org

Office Address: E111, Baoshan Campus, Shanghai University, Shanghai, 200444, China.

Google Scholar Page: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=fEp-jzkAAAAJ&hl=en

**Linkedin Profile:** http://uk.linkedin.com/in/lee-a-burton/ **ORCiD:** 0000-0002-0647-5483

# **Professional Summary**

Status: Associate Professor (full time).

Affiliations: Member of the Royal Society of Chemistry.

Accolades: - Chinese National Science Foundation International Young Scientist Award 2019.

- Shanghai Municipal Government Eastern Young Scholar Award 2018.

- European Commission Seal of Excellence Award 2017.

- Japanese Material Research Society Award for Encouragement of Materials

Research Science 2012.

Publications: 24 peer-review research articles; 4 international patents covering 13 inventions.

Metrics: More than 1,600 citations, h-index: 16, 4 first-author papers with >130 citations.

Funding Awards: Early career fellowship, 2 International Research Fellowships, PhD Scholarship.

Languages: English (native), French (conversational), Mandarin (basic).

### Qualifications

**Doctoral Qualification:** PhD in Sustainable Chemical Technologies, University of Bath, UK.

Undergraduate Degree: Master of Chemistry (Hons), University of Warwick, UK.Other Qualifications: Master of Research (Merit), University of Bath, UK.

Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française (B1), Université Catholique de Louvain.

#### **Key Skills Summary**

- Project management, team-leading, task delegation and international collaboration.
- Programming proficiency in Python 2/3, Bash and LaTeX languages.
- Project proposal, bid evaluation and persuasive writing.
- Control of Substances Hazardous to Health (COSHH) and risk assessment practices.
- Numerical and technical analysis, software and computer literacy.
- Budget management, resource allocation and account keeping.
- Multi-disciplinary teamwork, event organisation and laboratory management roles.
- Presentation and public engagement experience, 3D visualisation software, image rendering.
- Teaching, lecturing, online recording and demographic awareness.

# **Employment History**

## Feb. 2019 to Present – Associate Professor, Shanghai University, China.

- Recipient of Shanghai Eastern Young Scholar early career fellowship, 2019.
- Recipient of the Chinese National Science Foundation International Young Scientist Award, 2019.
- Tenured faculty position in the Department of Physics and guest lecturer in international development.
- Tutorial leader at the 2019 Jiangsu mathematics & computing in materials design graduate summer school.
- Invited speaker at two international conferences and one international workshop.
- Recipient of Royal Society of Chemistry small equipment research fund.
- 5 research papers published to date including invited article selected as cover for J. Mat. Chem. C. emerging investigators special issue 2020 and contributed article selected as cover for J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2020.

# Dec. 2016 to Feb. 2019 – Research Fellow, Université Catholique de Louvain, Belgium.

- Recipient of "Move-In Louvain" research fellowship funded by the EU Marie-Curie actions.
- Recipient of the European Commission Seal of Excellence award 2018.
- Invited speaker & session chair at European Materials Research Society (E-MRS) Meetings 2017 & 2018.

# Lee Alan Burton

- B1 level Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française (DELF) qualification obtained.
- 2 international patents granted, contribution purchased by Panasonic Corporation.
- Tutorial leader on database querying & high-throughput screening at Materials Research Society (MRS)
   Spring Meeting, USA, 2018.

# Nov. 2014 to Nov. 2016 -Research Fellow, Tokyo Institute of Technology, Japan.

- Royal Society nominated candidate for maximally funded fellowship with Japanese Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS).
- Equal shareholder on international patent for 11 novel semiconductors (number WO/2017/065294).
- Speaker at four international conferences and invited contribution to international workshop.
- 5 research articles published in high impact journals including Nature Comms. and Phys. Rev. Lett.
- Japanese language classes and culture engagement activities attended throughout the fellowship.
- Volunteer participant of JSPS Science Dialogue program: lecturing at senior high schools (ages 15-17).

# Oct. 2010 to Oct. 2014 - Doctoral Student, University of Bath, UK.

- Multi-disciplinary PhD funded by Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council scholarship.
  - Recipient of Award for Encouragement of Materials Research Science by Japanese Materials Research Society.
  - o Over 2,000 GBP in external grant money and bursary awards.
- Laboratory custodian of Solar Instrument Room, Department of Chemistry.
  - o Developed control and safety standards for contemporary lab space.
  - o Implemented training and operating protocols for hazardous experimental procedures.
- Public engagement and ambassadorial roles for the Centre for Sustainable Chemical Technologies.
  - Elected Ambassador to the UK Energy Research Network for the Bath graduate school.
  - o Invited speaker for the British Science Association's 'Science Café' public presentation.
  - o University of Bath STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics) ambassador.
- Taught-lab demonstrator and part-time teaching assistant.

## Dec. 2013 to May 2014 - Events Manager, "Pint of Science" festival, Bath, UK.

• Theme leader of 'Planet Earth' section, Bath chapter, for international science festival 'Pint of Science'.

# Nov. 2013 to Apr. 2014 – Conference Organiser, Royal Society of Chemistry, UK.

- Organising committee member for the RSC, Solid State Group Easter Meeting, Buckinghamshire, UK.
- Responsibilities included: budget allocations, costing, talk selection and program design.

# Jul. 2013 to Dec. 2013 - Visiting Scholar, Harvard University, USA.

- Established international collaboration between the University of Bath (UK), Harvard University (USA) and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (USA).
- Involved multiple visits between UK & USA, confidential data handling and regular teleconferencing.

## Oct. 2010 to Sep. 2011 - Master of Research, University of Bath, UK.

• Degree with taught courses and 2 research projects: battery cathodes and materials for hydrogen storage.

## Apr. 2009 to Sep. 2009 – Research Intern, University of Tasmania, Australia.

• Designed and built a 2-D gas chromatography suite to analyse oil spills for the Australian Antarctic Division.

#### References on Request **Professor Aron Walsh**, **Professor Fumiyasu Oba Professor Jeffrey Reimers** (PhD Supervisor) (Post-Doctoral Supervisor) (Current Institute Director) Laboratory for Materials & Structures, Royal School of Mines. School of Mathematical and Imperial College London, Tokyo Institute of Technology, Physical Sciences, University of London, SW7 2BP, Yokohama 226-8503, Technology Sydney, Sydney, United Kingdom. Australia. Japan. oba@msl.titech.ac.jp a.walsh@imperial.ac.uk jeffrey.reimers@uts.edu.au